# Solmaz Seyed Monir

Seattle, WA

solmazseyedmonir8 rc5@indeedemail.com

+1 630 854 3065

Website

https://solmazsm.github.io/develop/

https://solmazsm.github.io/

https://solmazsm.github.io/solmazfolio/

Experienced in software development and implementation. Involved in hands-on development using OOP, Java/J2EE technologies

Expertise in Core Java with strong understanding and working knowledge of Object-Oriented Concepts like Collections,

Multi-Threading, Concurrency Framework

Expert in UML, Design methodologies and design patterns

Expertise in application development frameworks like Struts, Spring, and Hibernate & Angular Js Extensive knowledge in working with J2EE technologies such as Servlets, JSP, JDBC, EJB, Java Beans, JMS and

Object-Oriented Programming techniques

Expertise in developing front - end systems with JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, MVC frameworks such as

Angular JS as a platform for Web applications

Experience in major web application servers: Apache Tomcat, JBoss, Express

Expertise in various open-source frameworks like Struts 2.x, 1.x, Spring, JSF, Ext JS and ORM

Technology like

Hibernate

Strong RDBMS concepts including expertise in PL/SQL queries like DML, DDL, Stored Procedures, Views, User

Defined Functions (UDF), Triggers, and Cursors etc.

Experience in implementing web-based projects using Web/Application Servers such as Web Logic Apache Tomcat, and

WebSphere

# Work Experience

## Full Stack Developer -data Analysis - Intern

instahub - Remote

October 2021 to Present

- I joined the Web Development team who is responsible for designing, coding, and modifying websites, from layout to function and according to specifications. I strive to create visually appealing sites that feature user-friendly design and clear navigation for customers to access building analytics for the energy management systems and our alert system. I work alongside the marketing team to improve InstaHub communication of the company environmental/social impact and product value proposition.
- Set up REST API, database, connect instances and routing strategies
- Using Python-SQL-Cloud (EC2-VPC-S3-network- RDS-AWS Lambda)

• Be responsible for the design, planning and management of the AWS cloud infrastructure.

# **Full Stack Developer**

SIERRA CONSULTING - Chicago, IL April 2020 to August 2020

- Led a group project created by Java and Angular. Application has three parts and developed login and CRUD backend and frontend. Frontend was written by Angular, and bootstrap and backend were written by JAVA Spring Boot, MySQL.
- Expanded a blog about datacenter. http://535fall2018solmazmonir.blogspot.com

## **Software Developer**

RASA TECHNOLOGY ENGINEERING - Tehran, IR

• Designed and invented a website promotional too automates process of promoting client's web sites on internet. •

Consulted with managerial, engineering, and technical personnel to clarify program intent, identified problems, and suggested changes. • Performed validation of completed sites including debugging and testing of code. • invented and maintained intranet and internet for company Websites utilizing • created and designed a user-friendly interface for online programs multimedia systems and Web-driven Email. • established and devised graphics including icons and logos using Fireworks and Photoshop. • Responsible for design and development of Internet, websites, and web applications. (www.rasatech.com)

# **Software Developer**

RASATECH FZ Ras - al Khaimah, UAE

• Devised visual websites applied by photoshop, Dreamweaver, flash, and more

#### **Education**

# PhD in Computer Science and Systems

University of Washington 2021 to 2023

#### **Master in Information Technology Infrastructure**

ILLINOIS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY Chicago - Chicago, IL 2017 to 2019

# Master in Information Technology Management Advanced Information Systems

AZAD UNIVERSITY Tehran

#### **Bachelor in Computer Software Engineering**

UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND CULTURE Tehran

#### Skills

- Teamwork
- Leadership

- Problem-solving
- Flexibility
- · Conflict resolution
- Effective communication skills
- Initiative
- Organization
- CSS 3
- HTML5
- XML
- jQuery
- JavaScript
- Java
- Database
- Angular
- React
- Python
- AWS
- Cloud
- Version Control
- Spring Boot
- JDBC
- NoSQL's
- JSON
- Networking
- Data Analysis
- SAS
- J2EE Technologies
- Servlets
- JSP
- JMS
- ApacheTomcat5x
- JBoss 5.0
- Hibernate

# Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/solmaz-seyedmonir